[Music]
arvand welcome to Stanford thank you
thank you for having me I'm from
Berkeley hopefully you don't
mind at least wanted to represent with
the
blue but yeah it's great to be here
thank you we're happy to have you here
today now many of us in the audience are
active perplexity users thank you
especially with free perplexity Pro for
all Stanford students
so we couldn't be more excited to have
you here thank you now to get started I
figured I would turn to perplexity to
help me craft my questions so let's take
a look at what it
said so to get started I figured I would
put this prompt into perplexity and I
asked I'm interviewing Arvin for a
1-hour interview at Stanford with an
audience of business school students
what questions should I ask him
now hopefully they're not they not too
difficult well you probably missed that
in the prompt uh you might have yourself
to blame for that
one so perplexity did give me a very
detailed response but in summary it
suggested that we talk about first your
personal
backstory second the early days of
perplexity third the company today and
fourth various Leadership Lessons how
does that sound sounds
good I thought that sounded like a
pretty good outline but I figured we
could get just a little more
personal so I thought I would test out
my follow-up prompting skills and I
asked
perplexity what is something about
aravan that the audience may not
know what is the funniest thing about
him what are some questions that I can
ask him to inject humor into this
conversation
very
direct what are some rapid fire
questions I can ask you at the end of
the interview so stay tuned for that and
finally is perplexity ever
wrong more more more than you
think so this generated some more
interesting insights than my initial
prompt uh including here's the very
detailed list but I'll just hit on a few
of them first I learned that you love
cricket
second I discovered that you actually
taught yourself to program after missing
getting into computer science at I
madress by only 0.01
points and lastly I learned about your
connection to Sundar Pai the CEO of
Google who grew up in the same Hometown
in chenai
India now perplexity actually suggested
that I watch this video of you and you
and Sundar from chai so I figured that
this might be a very good place for us
to start I'll spare you the video but
arvand is there something in the water
in chenai that's led to so many
successful Tech
entrepreneurs well I I think like it's
interesting you know like
um more than I'm sure like a lot of
people in India like you know there's so
many cities which are producing great
people and um uh so one thing that I
would say is very common is the sort of
culture of um really trying to Excel and
do your best at what what you meant to
do uh and the sort
of like real emphasis on
education is very much present in
Chennai and many other cities of course
but like in in at least in my circles um
people valued being scholarly and well
read even more than being rich like it
you kind of got respected a lot for it
and I think that translates to like you
know going above and beyond and uh not
just read what's meant for your exam to
do well in your exam but like really try
to go deep into what you're trying to
learn um and I think that's sort of like
common in many people who come from
there and Excel in Silicon Valley or
other parts of the US uh I feel that
it's like a very common trait uh and
obviously like this cricet thing is
there and like one thing chai is known
for uh is they call the cricket nerds
like they really obsessed about all the
statistics
you know like back before like uh Google
or like Crick info or all these sites
existed uh we could still like you know
recite all the stats of every player uh
and and like obsess about things like
what's the run rate what's the average
and like you you learn like basic
statistics before even it's start
formally to you that like it's not just
important to score a lot of runs in one
game but like you got to be pretty
consistent and so um I think that's kind
of common I would say for people from I
so knowledge over wealth and attend
cricket games that's what I'll take away
from that one now you left India to
pursue your PhD in computer science at
UC Berkeley not Stanford
unfortunately oh I I I didn't get in
here that's the
truth well we have you here today we
couldn't be luckier but how have your
academic Roots shaped your approach to
building perplexity yeah it's it's
actually like pretty core um you know
for black City started off with
citations right after every answer and
this is obviously like real I'm not not
just making it up when I first went to
Berkeley and I thought PhD is is amazing
thing you watch movies about like
Stephen Hawking where you just knock on
your advises the this is the idea for my
thesis like I I really romanticize how
that's how it's going to be but it's not
quite as uh uh like you know easy as
that like you have to like kind of earn
your way to like coming up with your
first core original idea idea so um it's
institutions like Berkeley or Stanford
they've kind of like amazing because
they uh give the new student a sort of
like a framework to get there instead of
just leaving them uh completely
unsupervised um and so when I first went
to the lab uh I was asked to kind of
help a senior student uh by like you
know work on their idea and like try to
actually make it really work and write a
paper you learn the process and then you
kind of like Get from there so um after
I wrote like a paper or two um they told
me this concept of citations and so what
matters is not necessarily you getting a
paper accepted it's that other people
have to site and build on it that's how
you build your academic currency in the
community and um I was like okay that's
cool but like my paper seems like too
complicated so there's always this
trade-off between writing very
complicated uh like very uh creative
ideas that might get the reviewers to
accept your paper but for someone else
to build on it like if it's too
complicated nobody cares so I think like
you want that sweet spot of like very
simple ideas that will get cited but
also will get accepted in a conference I
had to learn it the hard way and once I
learned that I I kind of obsessed about
citations and uh you know I also learned
that that was the core inspiration for
the Google search engine of how academic
citation graph to like marrying that
idea to the web hyperlinks so um that
sort of also uh came into perplexity
because we asked the question okay what
if like an AI always responded like an
academic when you write a paper every
sentence you write in an academic paper
needs to have a corresponding citation
to it or else it's kind of coming across
like an opinion uh it needs to be uh
something that like a source of truth
from some other peer-reviewed paper in
the past or some experimental result in
your own paper and we thought okay what
if we do that for U AI where every
answer every sentence in the answer
needs to come from some Source in the
web that has some amount of domain
Authority or trust core and and if we
can um uh bake that into the prompt it's
like U inbuilt then that sort of creates
a very unique product experience and
that's actually how my academic Roots
help me in perplexity now I know
perplexity is academic Focus feature has
been a key driver of adoption here at
Stanford and lets you cite only academic
journals in your research so very
helpful for all of us who are studying
today now at perplexity you're very
focused on improving access to
information and you're building the
world's first answer engine why is
democratizing access to knowledge so
important to you because I I love using
it myself like I think uh like I said
right I I come from a culture where uh
being knowledgeable was very valued uh
there is even this code from Charlie
manger where the best thing you can do
for another human being is to help them
learn and know more uh and and it's
almost like a moral duty for all of us
to seek wisdom and become Perpetual
learning machines because nothing else
can help us like keep upgrading
ourselves like there's only like you can
you can probably focus on wealth and
your net worth you can try to use that
as a metric for you know your pro your
progress in life but at some point like
it Taps out it stops m ating you if you
reach a certain threshold on the other
hand uh there is no end to knowledge uh
that's why in perplexity the tagline is
where knowledge begins because there's
actually truly no end to knowledge uh
and um you know you can you can only
keep getting better so if there's one
metric ultimately that we can converge
to uh to view ourselves as like making
progress on that it's just understanding
the world better so if that uh is so
core the human nature uh it's essential
that all of us have access to the tools
that help us get there in the most
accessible way and we're trying to do
our best to do that and obviously like
you know the more premium services are
behind pay walls but um as these AI
models are getting cheaper and like
smarter more efficient more like
distilled into smaller versions um it's
it's going to be possible to create a
version that's just widely accessible
for all and helps them basically ask any
question they wanted and get an instant
answer where knowledge begins yeah
exactly I love that now I want to go
back to the Genesis of perplexity to
tackle such a big problem you needed a
great team so what qualities did you
look for and how did you build your
initial founding team yeah uh I was
lucky enough to know uh one of my
co-founders Dennis uh during my PhD days
uh this is also where like the academic
background helps you a lot like you uh
learn people who are like very motivated
and uh deep thinkers and so we wrote the
same paper like the literally the same
idea a day apart and uh so that's how we
got to know each other and he spent some
time um as a visiting student in my lab
and um we used to brainstorm ideas on
like what we could do together but
nothing really came out of it uh one
quality I would say like you look for
your founding team is like obviously
people with complimentary skills uh you
don't want to be uh as good as them and
what they excel at ideally they should
be a lot better and uh also you don't
want to like step on their toes when
they do that uh and in in our case like
it's kind of like Dennis and Johnny are
were my like core founding team and um I
would say Johnny was world number one at
competitive programming he represented
United States at the II and um those who
are aware of competitive programming
there used to be this kind guy called
tourist um and and like only one guy has
beaten him in the II ever and that was
Johnny um so that sort of like Prodigy
who can like not just write amazing code
but has the problem solving skills to
like like instantly solve hard problems
quickly and the sort of like AI depth
and background and software engineering
background that Dennis had uh combined
together with like allowed me to like
take bold risks and uh try to set up the
sort of very overarching mission of
trying to build a completely new search
experience otherwise it's impossible
like forget about like trying to do this
right like so um and then over time like
you try to hire more and more people who
can um bring in new skills obviously
none of the three of us have front-end
programming skills so we hired someone
like really good at like the full stack
experience and we hired someone really
good at writing Kura kernels like it it
keeps on like like uh becoming an
incremental additive as well as
multiplicative Force um and I think that
that sort of um effect is necessary when
there's a lot of people who are it's not
like I think there's a under like like a
mental model of like vector sum of all
the people but I actually think uh if
you want to create even like like a
truly great company uh there needs to be
some kind of this La ofala effect like
there's uh factors that become U
multiplic ative nature uh and and one
example I can give is like our design
team was very well known too but that's
not none of the founding team had that
design quality so we went and uh hired
someone specifically for that where that
person actually wanted to build a
product like this but he did not have
the AI background or depth he used to
work at Kora where humans came and
answered questions so when we gave him
the platform to use this AI to be able
to answer questions like his imagination
skills came came in and created
something that's completely like
multiplicative and uh that's kind of how
I've generally tried to scale up the
team find the people who multip
multiplicate you yeah exactly yeah so
less than a year later you're in the
middle of raising your series a
financing round when you find out that
one of your key competitors open AI has
just launched their own search
competitor so when you heard the news
how did you respond and what gave you
the confidence that there was still room
for perplexity so this was you're asking
me about my series A the series a and
the news that open AI has a search
competitor yeah yeah but actually like
just just a correction there the at that
time open AI wasn't launching search it
was actually Microsoft was going to
launch Bing and um I I this is almost
like a Silicon Valley Story the TV show
kind of story where you know we we were
at the office of Nea and like we hand
Shook on a set of terms there and um and
then like you know I went to Blue Bottle
pal all to here you app with my with
Dennis and we're just chilling okay
finally it's done uh and then um The
Verge publishes a story of being
releasing on Monday and screenshots were
already leaked because of some a test
and uh you know in in um Venture F
funding there's this period called due
diligence like 30 days uh in fact some
another VC would also offered us a term
sheet after seeing that they increased
the diligence from 30 days to 45 days
and I was like okay like this doesn't
seem quite right like you know maybe
they trying to back out here and um and
then the Nea also like calls me on
Saturday morning hey do you have time
for a phone call on Saturday morning I
was like okay maybe they just going to
say like uh uh they want to back out but
they actually said look no we believe in
you we saw the my Microsoft thing uh
don't worry about it uh you'll figure
out a way we you know like so we're not
going to back out of the deal and um you
keep going so that gave us a lot of
confidence and uh I feel I felt like
that was very crucial because I've heard
like lots of stories of how you get term
sheets and actually don't get the
funding but they like were True
Believers yeah luckily your investors
had your back and as the underdog you
must have needed a creative several
times when fundraising and you've been
very successful at it you've attracted
Jeff Bezos from Amazon Yan laon the
Godfather of AI and even Nvidia so how
did you assemble such a great group of
investors and what War Stories can you
tell
us well this is funny story like um
Dennis was an NYU so he kind of already
uh knew Yan um but obviously Yan is a
celebrity it's so hard to reach him so
Yan was on a vacation in in in in in
France for a long time and we just heard
he came back uh to new the NYU campus so
um we were already in New York at the
time so we we just basically camped in
front of his office um for like multiple
hours and he went for lunch and like
like yeah you guys are waiting okay fine
like I'll come back and then we finally
got like half an hour with them and we
built this search over Twitter demo uh
where all we had to do is like let him
search over his own tweets and who's
replying to him and like uh how many
followers does he have that all those
kind of interesting questions everybody
has for themselves and he allowed it and
he's like okay fine like I want to
invest like he just made the decision
like uh 10 minutes of using the product
same thing happened with um you know
like other other investors like karpati
you know he's a celebrity here uh he he
he asked for a deck and I just sent him
the uh the link to directly try the
product and and and same thing with Jeff
Dean all these people were just um
impressed by just using the product so
so the the the main takeaway here is uh
you know there's this thing called a
circle of competence if you're not good
at making decks don't try to like do it
right and I I wasn't good at it so
instead just make sure there is a link
that they can actually use or try
instantly and make sure it works because
there are some people who do do that who
that and like the moment you just click
on it it just crashes or it doesn't work
that's not a good experience but if it
works I think it communicates a lot more
than uh having a deck because number one
most people don't have the time they're
on their phones they're not like on
their computers like reading every small
part of the deck you optimize for so um
the other thing is if you're not good at
it like like me um then don't try to do
it and by the way I haven't really done
decks much even for our series a was
very minimal um series B no decks
CD like I just write memos or notion
documents um I actually try not to do it
because I'm just not good at it so I I I
there was there's even like a lot of
successful decks from the past uh like
Airbnb LinkedIn
Facebook and you you see all that and
you're just even more confused how to
make one cuz they're all so different
and you don't know which one to copy or
like how to be original
you know like what is and it it it's
very confusing so I just never tried to
do
it so play to your strengths instead of
being a copycat yeah it's a good lesson
you have a lot of perspective
entrepreneurs in the audience and so I
think this is a good reminder that it
takes great determination and and hard
work and that that can really pay off or
like you don't have to be really good at
many things like that people may like if
you can be founder CEO and not know how
to make Tex it's fine yeah you have a
lot of Consultants here who all we do is
make slide decks so maybe we have the
opposite the opposite skill set be a
good team to put the two together now at
perplexity you're building an answer
engine but you don't own the content and
you don't own the models so what is your
technical moat and why is the perplexity
approach better than direct vertical
integration she's politely asking me why
you're just a rapper so tell us how are
you going to those are your words not
mine
yeah but yeah like like this is kind of
like actually I would be uh one year ago
like the whole um Community was pretty
divided on which startups to invest in
or like which kind of startups to build
should should these companies be
training their own models or should they
be like using apis and um we had a
conviction that number one models are
going to get increasingly commoditized
uh that and if you do want to be one of
those players that that build their like
like our our provider of the models you
need to have an insane amount of funding
and you need to be uh a company that is
losing billions of dollars a year and
it's still fine and uh we didn't want to
be we were not in a position to be and
we didn't want to be either so we
decided to use other people's models and
shape them to be really good for a
endend consumer experience of searching
and you know we felt like there was a
lot to do outside the model uh there and
um I think that bet ended up being right
in the sense there are a lot of
companies that were trying to build
their models who no longer
exist uh and I think that uh was a clear
uh proof point that like you know you
either raise 10 billion or you don't do
this thing at all you do something else
and and and for us we were like working
on uh giving answers to people and is if
the answer to this question for for
giving accurate answers to everybody do
you need to build your own Foundation
models uh if the answer to that question
is an absolute yes yes we should we
shouldn't be doing this thing without
raising 10 billion but I felt like if
open source makes progress and models
keep getting cheaper uh the cost of like
these apis is going down 2x every four
months so assume that Trend continues
for another year or two we're at least
going to write the wave of a 10 to 100x
reduction in the cost for the same
intelligence
and the level of intelligence and
reasoning is also going up and open
source is keeping a check on these
closed Source models and bringing the
price down it's a perfect time to be an
application layer company using these
models and like post trining them to be
good at summarization referencing
formatting custom uis for like so many
different verticals Finance Sports uh
you know reasoning all these kind of
like charts there's so many things to do
outside the model that we felt like it
was just completely worth it to build a
different shate business and at the end
like most successful businesses are
rappers of some form right like uh
before they existed something else was
the more valuable thing and then uh
something comes on top uh there's even a
thing of like Coca-Cola wouldn't have
really worked if the refrigeration
technology did not exist right but
Coca-Cola is an extremely valuable
direct to consumer product and so you
can always create something that's some
magic formula the right packaging uh
that works with the foundational
technology but in the hands of the
consumer provides immense value to them
that it's totally worth uh building and
so that's what we want to be what should
you build yourself and when can you
leverage things that already exist yeah
it's a great strategy now you've been
openly critical of Google's overreliance
on advertising and yet just this past
week perplexity announced that it was
also introducing advertising for the
very first
time so what is your monetization
strategy and how big of a role role will
ads play in the future yeah so um
perplexity ads are different from
Google's ads uh we Google's ad the
problem is the same ad unit is is Al
Whatever is the answer unit is also the
ad unit there in the sense Google gives
you a a bunch of links as like you know
for most queries and that is also the
unit an Advertiser can influence by
paying so that way when you're looking
for Relevant answers uh information
and if the ordering of the links was
manipulated with ads it frustrates you
uh if we can avoid the Trap and pick an
ad unit that's lower margins lower
profits yet like allows us to be true to
our users and still make money it's a
reasonably better or like say I would
say much better Sweet Spot than what
Google went for and um we said okay like
there's an answer that should be
unbiased and truthful to whatever you
ask for but after the answer there are a
bunch of questions uh that we suggest
you to ask next you don't have to
literally ask that but at least it
influences you on what you want to ask
next and U let's say you're sh like like
having a shopping related query of like
you know I'm looking for running shoes
and this is exactly what I want and like
uh these are the brands I like and it
gives you an answer uh the follow-up
question that we could suggest there is
some uh shoe brand that tries to get
your attention there uh which could be
like what makes makes Adidas better than
Nike for tennis or something like that
right uh that's a qu question they might
have picked because your first question
was probably I'm looking for shoes for
playing tennis and that's a very high
intent question compared to just a ADW
of a shoe but we're not like making a
particular brand appear one in front of
the other on the original answer but we
could still get your attention on the
brand as a follow-up question you can
choose to ignore it too so that is an
unit that we are experimenting with and
uh we working with a few Brands who are
willing to try it out first of all uh
the major concern is right now for
Brands they're afraid like how the
answer can come out to be because they
don't really control the answer no brand
is influencing the answer they're only
able to pick the question so uh it first
takes courage for some Brands to come
and experiment this FR uh you know style
the ROI is not exactly like clear
because it's not uh necessarily driving
a lot of traffic to you
so um it's still very early days for us
but what we are very very clear on is um
not trying to influence the accuracy and
truthfulness of the answer because once
we do that then we're going to end up in
the same path as uh Google where people
are like frustrated with the answer so
when I type my initial prompt for
example for this interview I will never
see an ad response okay it's re
reassuring to
hear now perplexity is obviously
innovating very quickly and yet this
pace of innovation has attracted some
controversy so News Corp the parent
company of the Wall Street Journal has
sued you for copyright infringement M
the New York Times has also issued a
cease and assist order for inappropriate
content use how are you handling these
recent challenges and what is your
vision for ethical AI development yeah
so here here's what I uh we believe and
we've uh said this on our blog post too
uh no one has a copyright of or
ownership over truth or facts uh this is
true in the world of Journalism too if
there is an article for example right
now in our interview you referen that
the New York Times is s perplexity now
that was reported by somebody else but
you're using that in our interview now
can someone uh claim ownership over that
and disallow you from saying that
particular thing no right so truth is
supposed to be distributed widely right
so the specific expression of Truth the
specific way in which something is
written that that that has some
copyright angle there and that's
actually the core open AI New York Times
scenario but what we are doing is we are
referencing truth that already exists in
these outlets and summarizing and
synthesizing it for the user in the
context of a search experience so uh
people need to differentiate the use of
AI that trains on proprietary content
versus AIS that just use them as sources
and give answers and there's no actual
training happening so uh we made that
very clear in our response and uh We've
also made it clear that we want to like
we we can only survive and keep getting
better as a product if there is an open
and thriving ecosystem of Journalism
because we do need realtime information
to be created every single day and if
there's not the right Financial
incentive for them to do that then it's
not good
so what we did is like okay we're going
to make Revenue through ads and we're
going to share that ad Revenue with
Publishers and that way you you enter
into this publisher program that we came
up with which is not exactly paying you
money just to license your data for a
certain period of time and then once
we've absorbed it like we don't want to
like we don't want to create that sort
of a short-term model a long-term model
is as we scale in usage as we scale as a
business in Revenue we want to share
that Revenue with you on a query level
basis
so it's very clear this is more inspired
by how Spotify shares revenue and um
Fortune time DPO have all like signed up
to be part of it WordPress signed up to
be part of it and we're also going to
announce more Partners in the coming
weeks so we are very uh confident that
that program will soon resonate with
everybody in the journalism community
and we also made grants to Northwestern
University to kind of like do more
research on how uh tools like ours can
help journalists like you know write
better because all journalists do fact
checks and we are an amazing tool for
like doing fact checks so I I I'm very
confident that this current period of
turbulence will go away and uh a year or
two from now like we'll have a system
that uh helps both both these different
set of people to like flourish together
and just to follow up on that so earlier
today we talked about perplexity
academic roots and the importance of
citations yeah so given that how do you
handle these Journal allegations of
plagiarism in particular yeah so exactly
so that when you want to like go deeper
into the definition of plagiarism it's
like if you don't attribute the source
that's like a very core part of it uh
and when you're always attributing the
source it's very hard to say like you're
plagiarizing content uh and also like uh
you're not exactly reproducing things as
sure AIS are unreliable at times and
like there are times when there like
word overlap of like more than three or
four words and you can argue like to
what extent that is like you know uh
exact reproduction versus trying to
synthesize but what we are trying to say
is like we are trying our level best to
summarize synthesize from diverse set of
sources and make sure to give credit to
all the original sources and that way
like we um in our to to our uh best
possible extent we can control these AIS
uh we are doing our best to make sure
that the credit attribution part is
clear mhm I I like the Spotify analogy
it's just it's such a rapidly changing
land exactly so if you if we make an ad
Revenue where you're a source uh we're
going to share that Revenue with you uh
who never shared ad Revenue Google
because they gave you the traffic but
they made the ad revenue on their
platforms and uh the only way for you to
monetize the traffic that you get is to
put popups and ads on your site through
another product of their school AdSense
and so that is what frustrates many
users come directly read on uh many
journalist sites because there's a lot
of ads on the site they have to like you
know close a lot of popups and so it's
this system of like just referring
traffic and making you monetize with
more ads is not sustainable right like
we you need to create something that the
user really wants and and we're also
offering our apis so that they can build
AI native products and chat bots on
their their websites so if people want
to just come there and ask questions
about only articles that they have
written we're offering our apis for free
to these people and we're also offering
our tools for free to all the people who
work at a particular journalist Outlet
so that way like we we we can create a
system that U is economically pretty
lucrative for them that's it's an
interesting future ahead so if we take a
step back now and we think about the
biggest technology companies of all time
in almost every case these are category
creating companies Uber Facebook Airbnb
Salesforce so a decade from now if we
look back on this moment in time what is
the history defining company that you
are
building I would say like if we can help
people uh get answers to all their
questions and get help for all their
tasks uh we will be like a we we we'll
be in that league for sure and uh we are
getting pretty close to being a reliable
answer machine I know you asked
questions perplexity I wrong and I'm
telling you like there are a lot of
mistakes we still make on a daily basis
but uh zoom out and think like if models
keep getting better and our coverage of
the web is getting better uh the
mistakes are going to be like whatever
is like one in a 10 or one in 100 is
going to you know be reduced to like 1
in a, one in a 10,000 that order of
magnitude Improvement is going to come
so if we are a reliable answer machine
to everybody and widely accessible and
not just give you answers but help you
accomplish tasks too
make transactions buy things book Things
uh book flights get the best deals uh
and like you know make your life more
productive uh give you give give you
back all more time I think we're going
to be a pretty industry defining product
in a
company it's exciting we hope to see you
there a few years from now now there's
so much more we could talk about when it
comes to perplexity but I wanted to save
a few minutes to talk about you and your
leadership style so in just two years
you've progressed from a scrappy founder
to CEO to the leader of A9 billion AI
company M what does your leadership
Journey looked like across all of these
different
stages yeah I've tried my best to keep
keep upgrading um and I'm still not you
know the most
seasoned um polished
CEO but I would say there's an extreme
bias for Action that uh I try to like
bring in and try to like encourage
everybody else in the company to adopt
and I think that's what's helping us
continue to be fast even when you've
gotten it to about 100 people a Founder
that I really admired told me once you
get to 100 people you're going to you're
guaranteed to move slow and I was like
very determined to prove him wrong so so
far so good you know but at some point
like definitely we're going to hit the
uh problems of scale and like how to
move fast so I'm determined to solve
that problem and if whatever final
solution I come up with I hope it's
helpful for other people too and the
other thing I would say is giving people
who haven't
necessarily uh become experts at one
thing the opportunity to like go do
something they're not yet proven for uh
is something I've done a lot like uh you
don't have to hire the former head of
growth at Instagram to be like the head
of growth or head of product at
perplexity that's that's a trap that a
lot of people fall into it's like oh if
I want the best uh person for you know
doing ab tests I'm going to get the
person who did it at the previous best
consumer company and hire them here I
have not fallen into the scrap I've
actually tried to hire people with some
chips on their shoulders who are like
very talented but they have not had
their first major hit yet uh chips on
shoulders put chips in your pockets so
not my original codes so I I don't
remember who said this but it's uh it's
it's pretty cool so that that's
something that I wish more people did
the sort of like uh experimentation like
putting someone in the waters and
letting them figure out how to swim
rather than hiring the most uh you know
well-known expert at that topic main
reason is that like uh most people are
unable to push themselves for the second
success in general uh I've I've seen
that and um I think I think like it's
very hard to be extremely motivated to
do like uh grelling hours when you've
already had like big success in your
life so um that's one way I've tried to
be different and bias for Action trying
to do things on my own uh to understand
like what what it is and I use the
product quite a lot myself pretty much
like at least 10 queries a day is my
average but there are some users who do
it more than me so I'm very happy um and
and um I think like that helps me to
make the right decisions if at some
point you stop using your own product
that the company's building uh you it's
very easy to lose touch with reality and
you're just like making decisions based
on what other people tell you and um
it's very essential that you're as close
as possible to the source of Truth so
when people complain on social platforms
like Twitter oh this thing is not
working that thing's not working I low
doing customer support um I think we
have people who do customer support too
I'm not trying to say they're not needed
but it really helps you to like um um
understand what the customer frustration
is the user frustration is and be be
that sort of a user yourself like
complain about your own product to your
engineers your product managers say like
this should be fast this you know you
don't have to like uh uh sort of like
just be doing whiteboarding and strategy
all the time you can actually just sit
for hours and hours using your own
product and you can make better
decisions how we stay Scrappy at scale
yeah it's a great one to to stick with
so before we open it up to audience Q&A
I have one final question that we're
asking all of our speakers this year at
view from the top our theme is leaving
your mark So Arend how would you like to
be
remembered I would love for perplex I
mean myself and perplexity to be known
as helping the world like makes helping
make the world smarter if people who use
perplexity feel smarter after using it
because they learned something new uh
they slept wiser than when they go to
bed then they woke up I I would feel
really really glad if we accomplish that
uh because I think I think that's not
easy most products most consumer
products end up like wasting people's
times um like I you know there are
obviously not going to I'm not going to
mention but there are some products I I
am addicted to I use it a lot but I
don't feel good at the end like I wasted
so many hours um and um perplexity is
not that at least like I I don't think
it is that sort of a product that may
you know even the Discover feed that we
have people tell me that they learn
something when they scroll through it um
and I want that to be continue to be the
case and um I also want us to help
people do things like not a lot of
people can afford to have assistance
executive assistance personal assistance
and um I remember in 2018 when I was an
intern at open AI uh Sam Alman did this
fireside chat with Bill Gates and he
asked Bill Gates like what do you think
the world would look like when there is
Agi and the answer Gates gave was very
interesting he said it would it would
basically it would basically be like
living my life you
know live like a billionaire where if I
want to know about a topic if I want to
learn about a topic I don't have to read
any book I can have people read it for
me and give prepare a report for me and
even make a presentation for me if I had
to get somewhere I have a jet people
take care of all the travel planning
meals you know if I want to like work
out everything is like done I want the
best nutritionist I know what to eat I
don't have to think life is so easy it's
like running life on Cheat
Code now I think that sort of a life can
be made more and more accessible to most
people if AIS can do stuff for you truly
understand you you know help you plan
stuff help you book stuff like all the
mundane work that you have to do with on
the web if a tool can sort of
increasingly get better and better at
doing it I feel like your life will be
like uh a billionaire right and then the
meaning of the word billionaire also
sort of like loses significance over
time so um I think if we can be one such
to I'm not saying we want to be the only
tool but if we can be the one such tool
that helps people do that I feel like I
would have made a good Mark in the world
if perplexity can give me Bill Gates
life I will be very happy one
day now we'd like to open it up to
audience Q&A so if you have a question
please raise your hand and one of our
view from the top mic Runners will come
find you if you're selected stand up
State your question and year and ask
your
question Arin um firstly thank you I
think you're one of the young leaders we
all look up to given where we are today
um I'm a fan of the book Atomic habits
so in your journey from PhD student to
perplexity CEO what is the one habit you
had to or daily habit you had to let go
of and maybe a new one you learned that
helped you become the leader you are
today so the one habit I let go of uh
I'm not sure if I had to but I
definitely let go of this and I feel
like it helped me is uh waking up late
was just something I stopped doing
so
uh yeah I think it makes me feel like I
get more hours in the day um and so that
also means going to bed early like early
to bed early to rise you know that I I
feel like it helped me it's a very um so
it's it's been like probably at at least
two to maybe 3 to four years since I've
woken up later than 8:00 a.m. in the
morning and it doesn't matter which city
or where like I've always done this what
was the other other question and you
learn that you had to pick up
uh I think like I yeah at least trying
to get better at like getting you know
three days a week work
workouts and I I never used to work out
much before so
thank you for being here arind my name
is Shan I'm a second year MBA student
went to I Bombay for my dual degree
analytical engineering uh I think you
answered the technical mode question
really well but would like to hear from
you what do you think is the biggest
risk or challenge that you feel the
company's facing Sor sorry could you
repeat that uh what do you think is the
biggest risk or challenge that you feel
the company's facing today yeah um I I
think it's the same thing I said earlier
which is you know
um I think every startup that's try to
scale uh somehow ended up moving slower
once they got like several hundreds of
people a thousand people it's very
difficult to do somehow it gets
difficult to do things like you expect
progress to be at least linear in the
number of people you can do more
projects but it it gets very difficult
to simultaneously execute well without
some drop in quality and when there is a
drop in quality like users know no that
and they think like you know you
regressed your product has gotten worse
that's this whole phrase called
edification where when you're trying to
scale and like scale your business scale
your users uh product gets worse in
quality for the initial loyalists who
allowed it for the quality so I I that's
in my opinion the biggest challenge for
us hey I've got a followup to asen's
question earlier about the ethical
issues that per perplexity has been
facing I know that you personally have
experienced a lot of criticism
surrounding some of those issues and I
imagine that as a leader in those spaces
you spend a lot of time thinking about
that I'm curious how you've approached
ethical issues whose opinions you seek
out to inform yourself as you step into
bigger and bigger roles and if there's
an example where you've seen yourself
change your position on something really
important I'm sorry and I'm an mba1 oh
thank you so I think like uh we we have
a good set of people in our company uh
actually to for the publisher program
itself uh it's it's the brainchild of
like not our chief business officer
Dimitri um and um so clearly like you
know one thing that I've learned is you
know I just because I'm the CEO doesn't
mean I have to be the Sol the one who
solves every problem uh if someone's
better than me at doing something you
should trust their instincts there uh
one thing I did no believe in is like
it's there's a lot you can do by just
engaging uh and like trying to educate
people on the other side of what you're
trying to do uh I'll give you an
instance like Forbes obviously was um
pretty unhappy with some of our attempts
to like you know do pages and things
like that um but when I actually met the
person who criticized me on
Twitter and explained what we doing he
he at least like shook hands and said oh
I never understood this is exactly what
you're trying to do and um so I think
like there's more work to be done there
I haven't met everybody in the community
uh who's talking about us and I think
just trying to like there's even
something right when there is even a
sign of war or like it's foggy around
there it feels like something might bad
might happen the first thing you got to
do is uh make a phone call
and and and talk so that's what I intend
to
do so much for coming here um I'm Von M
MBA one student my computer science from
I khur you're a big inspiration thank
you um I really resonated with the point
where you said that you're trying to
help people find the answers they're
looking for but then also when you
talked about introducing ads in
suggestions where you you suggest like
uh why do you think Adidas is a better
shoe for sports than Nike or something
don't you think that affects the kind of
information or like the view that you're
presenting the users like that might not
be the answer they're looking for so
don't you think it's a question though
it's not it's not an answer um it's just
a suggested question but if you do
decide to engage with that
question the answer to that question is
still unbiased it's it's not something
um ders is influencing us to write
relative to the other brand and and and
the same way so uh at some point we
would really understand you quite deeply
enough that uh even those questions are
quite personalized to you and not a
generic uh sponsored question that the
brand picks and there has been evidence
that like you know for example a lot of
people uh feel like the Instagram ads
are pretty relevant to them uh and and a
lot of purchases happen as a result of
that so so I feel like relevance is the
true answer to making ads work and
making sure that it's not interfering
with the core value of the product which
is any question you ask if the answer to
that is uninfluenced by ads and it's
always going to be truthful the product
serves its value to you but if we want
to bring such a quality product which is
almost never wrong so you can trust what
it says at scale the company does need
to figure out like uh some intelligent
sweet spots of monetization too right
thank you so much I think we have time
for just one more question hi Arwin I
think this might be a good one to end
with by the way I'm a br I'm a mba1 so
as the co-founder of perplexity what is
the question that you find the most
perplexing this one
[Applause]
it's it's a great answer I'm glad I'm
glad you stopped there we do have one
final tradition here at vew from the top
where I asked you a set of Rapid Fire
questions and you respond with the first
thing that comes to mind okay for this
one I use perplexity to generate all of
these questions should be easy right
hopefully if you weren't the CEO of
perplexity what would you be doing right
now I'll probably be doing research
that's what I was doing before so this
AI research you're a cricket Enthusiast
what is your all-time favorite Cricket
moment when India won the World Cup in
2011 if you could have dinner with any
Tech Visionary Dead or Alive who would
it be Larry
pige I mean I'm not I'm not seeing
Steve Jobs Larry Page would be my my
piics bring them together dinner for
two and finally what is the strangest
search query you've seen on
perplexity so uh we released shopping on
Monday and uh we just looking at some of
the OTS and someone basically bought
this uh face mask that only has an
opening for the eyes and nothing else
and so either they're looking at it in
the context of skiing somewhere or like
biking somewhere that's really cold uh
or they're conducting a
heist and uh we weren't sure which so we
actually went and looked at the aquar
andar was like okay I'm really trying to
bike in this weather in the coming
months and I need something that can
like cover my face keep me warm let me
breathe but only has an opening for the
eyes that that was the intent level of
the query and then we got we got them
some pretty good answer that they just
bought a product right from
there well let's hope that the use case
was the former and not not the
latter that that's a great place for us
to wrap up so thank you so much Arvin
for being here it's been a
pleasure thank
[Music]
you for